RIGHT. AGENTS?
MA'AM.AGENT HIGHTOWER.
YEAH. ALL RIGHT. NARCOTICS
NEEDS HELP GETTING INTEL
ON A METH HOUSE
IN THE SOUTHWEST.
I SAID I COULD SPARE
TWO OF YOU.SURE. WE'LL GET IT.
VAN PELT AND CHO.
WHAT'S THE JOB?
[liquid drips]
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
THERE'S INTEL IN THESE.THERE BETTER BE.
IT'S DRIPPING ON MY FEET.
HIGHTOWER KNOWS ABOUT
RIGSBY AND ME.NOTICED THAT.
SHE KNOWS,
BUT SHE HASN'T SAID ANYTHING.
WHY DO YOU THINK THAT IS?NO IDEA.
IF YOU COULD GUESS.I WOULDN'T.
[sighs]
I CAN'T STOP
THINKING ABOUT IT.
[engine starts]THAT'S JUST GONNA GET YOU
IN TROUBLE.
CAN YOU HELP ME?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
I LOST MY SHOE.
CAN YOU TELL ME WHERE I AM?I'M--I'M GONNA CALL THIS IN,
ALL RIGHT?
MA'AM. MA'AM.
CAN YOU...
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA GET YOU
SOME MEDICAL ATTENTION. COME ON.OKAY.
COME OVER HERE AND SIT DOWN.OKAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
MM.
MA'AM?
GRACE.
HEY. SHE SAID
SHE CAN'T REMEMBER WHO SHE IS,
WHERE SHE CAME FROM
OR WHAT HAPPENED.
NO I.D.
NOTHING ON HER AT ALL.
WHERE'S LISBON?SHE'S ON HER WAY.
E.M.T.s THINK THE BULLET
GRAZED THE VICTIM'S HEAD.
I THOUGHT
WE SHOULD TALK TO HER HERE.
SHE LOST HER SHOE, SO SHE
COULDN'T HAVE WALKED FAR.
THE CRIME SCENE'S
PROBABLY NEARBY.GOOD THINKING.
[police radio chatter]SO SHOULD WE WAIT FOR LISBON
OR...
NAH. HI.
I'M PATRICK JANE.
HOW YOU DOING?
[panting] MY HEAD HURTS.
I DON'T REMEMBER WHO I AM.
[exhales deeply]
HOLD MY HAND.
I'M GONNA TRY
AND HELP WITH THE PAIN.
OKAY,
I WANT YOU TO CONCENTRATE
AND LET THE PAIN FLOW
OUT THROUGH YOUR ARM
AND INTO MY HAND.
JUST LET IT FLOW,
LIKE WATER.
AH, I CAN FEEL IT.
CAN YOU FEEL THAT?
YES.
CAN YOU FEEL IT FLOWING?YEAH.
THE PAIN IS FLOWING AWAY.
TELL ME YOUR NAME.
DON'T REACH.
JUST WAIT FOR IT.
I CAN'T.
AH, THAT'S OKAY.
THAT'S OKAY.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING THIS
MORNING, BEFORE YOU GOT HURT?
[whispers] I CAN'T.
IT'S OKAY. DON'T WORRY.[sniffles]
TONIGHT, THEN, BEFORE MY FRIENDS
FOUND YOU, WHAT WERE YOU DOING?
I-I WAS IN A ROOM.
IT'S COLD.
CAN YOU SEE ANYTHING?
IT'S--IT'S TOO DARK.
WERE YOU SITTING IN A CHAIR
OR WERE YOU LYING DOWN?
LYING DOWN.ON THE FLOOR OR ON THE BED?
ON THE FLOOR.
THERE'S...
DIRT AND STRAW.
[clears throat]
IT MAKES ME COUGH.
WHAT DOES IT SMELL LIKE?HORSES.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
GRACE?
YEAH. WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A STABLE.
YEAH.
[Patrick clears throat]
HER SHOE.
YEAH, THAT'S HER SHOE.
[Patrick] OKAY.
[Patrick clears throat]
OKAY.
[Patrick] ALL RIGHT.
[whispers] GUYS, THERE'S
A LIGHT SWITCH RIGHT HERE.
[click]
OH.
UH-OH.
THE BULLET CREASED HER SKULL.
IT DIDN'T FRACTURE THE BONE,
BUT A HIT LIKE THAT CAN KNOCK
YOU AROUND SOMETHING WICKED.
SHE COULD HAVE BEEN UNCONSCIOUS
FOR A WHILE.
SHOOTER PROBABLY THOUGHT
SHE WAS DEAD
AND DUMPED HER
WITH THE OTHER BODIES.WHAT ABOUT THE AMNESIA?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO TELL YOU.
RETROGRADE AMNESIA
USUALLY RECEDES WITH TIME,
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW FAST
THAT'LL HAPPEN.
OKAY, WHAT I WANT YOU TO DO IS
JUST FOCUS ON THE QUEEN.
HERE'S THE LADY.
NOW YOU SAW WHERE SHE IS.
THERE'S THE LADY.
OKAY. NOW TELL ME...
WHERE'S THE QUEEN?
WRONG.
FIRST BOY YOU EVER KISSED.
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT'S YOUR FIRST NAME?I DON'T KNOW. I'M SORRY.
LOOK, THERE SHE WAS.
SHE WAS ALWAYS THERE.
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.AND THE POINT BEING?
OH, I'M JUST MAKING SURE
SHE HAS AMNESIA,
WHICH, BY THE WAY, YOU DO.
IT'S HARD TO LIE WHEN YOU'RE
THINKING ABOUT SOMETHING ELSE.
[whispers] GREAT.WE'RE CHECKING
OUR MISSING PERSONS DATABASE,
THEN WE'LL RUN YOUR PRINTS.
SOMETHING'LL PROBABLY COME UP.[cell phone rings]
FIND SOMEBODY TO COME IN
AND PRINT HER.OKAY.
AGENT HIGHTOWER.MORNING, LISBON.
AS SOON AS IT'S PRACTICAL,
I WANT TO SEE YOU, VAN PELT
AND RIGSBY IN MY OFFICE.
I'VE BEEN MEANING TO ADDRESS
THIS ISSUE FOR A WHILE,
BUT THERE'S BEEN SO MUCH
COMING ACROSS MY DESK,
I HAVEN'T HAD THE TIME.
FIRST OFF,
NEITHER OF YOU IS DENYING
YOU'RE IN
A SEXUAL RELATIONSHIP?
ARE YOU?NO.
NO, MA'AM.YOU WORK TOGETHER,
YOU DEVELOP FEELINGS.
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
BUT YOU KNOW VERY WELL
IT'S AGAINST CBI RULES,
AND LIKE I TELL MY KIDS,
RULES ARE RULES.
IF YOU WANT TO STAY TOGETHER,
THAT'S YOUR CHOICE.
BUT ONE OF YOU HAS TO TRANSFER
OUT OF THE UNIT.
IF YOU BOTH WANT
TO STAY IN THE UNIT,
THEN YOU CAN'T BE TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
GIVE ME YOUR DECISION
TOMORROW AT THE LATEST.
QUESTIONS?
NO, MA'AM.NO.
OKAY.
LISBON, STAY A MOMENT.
WHY DIDN'T YOU HANDLE
THIS SITUATION YOURSELF?
I WON'T DEFEND
WHAT I DID, MA'AM--
I UNDERSTAND THESE TWO
SNEAKING AROUND,
BUT YOU'RE THEIR SUPERIOR.
I EXPECT MORE.
[sighs]
I'LL BE WRITING
A CORRECTIVE MEMO.
THAT'S IT.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
I DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT.
CHO, WHERE ARE WE
WITH THE VICTIMS?
I VERIFIED THE TWO I.D.s
WE FOUND AT THE SCENE.
JANINE AND MITCHELL LANGHAM
FROM CHICO,
BOTH IN THEIR 50s,
NO FAMILY IN STATE.
NEIGHBOR SAID THAT THEY WERE
HIKING IN KASTEN STATE FOREST.THAT'S 100 MILES
FROM WHERE WE FOUND THEM.
WELL, WHAT ABOUT
THE THIRD VICTIM?SAME AS THE JANE DOE.
NO I.D. OF ANY KIND.
THE CORONER SAYS
HE'S IN HIS EARLY 20s.
I PUT HIS PRINTS
INTO THE SYSTEM.VAN PELT, DID YOU GET
ANY HITS ON THEM? VAN PELT?
UH, I'LL CHECK. I'LL CHECK.THE CORONER THINKS
THAT THEY WERE SHOT
WITH A HIGH-POWERED RIFLE--
THE LANGHAMS UP CLOSE,
OUR JANE DOE
AND THE UNIDENTIFIED MALE
FROM A DISTANCE.DO EITHER OF THE LANGHAMS
HAVE A RECORD?
NO.I THINK WE CAN SET
THE LANGHAMS ASIDE.
I THINK THEY WERE BY-PRODUCTS.
WEREN'T PLANNED.OH?
YEAH. THE FIRST TWO VICTIMS
WERE SHOT FROM A DISTANCE,
I.D.s WERE TAKEN.
TWO VICTIMS WERE SHOT UP-CLOSE.
I.D.s WERE NOT TAKEN.
CLEARLY, THE FIRST TWO VICTIMS
WERE THE TARGETS.AND WHEN THE LANGHAMS
ROLL UP TO THE SCENE,
WRONG PLACE, WRONG TIME.
KILLER SHOOTS THE LANGHAMS,
FREAKS OUT.
DOESN'T BOTHER
TO TAKE THEIR I.D.s.
DOESN'T EVEN NOTICE
THAT ONE OF THE FIRST VICTIMS
THAT HE SHOT WAS ONLY WOUNDED.
WE GOT A HIT
ON THE MALE VICTIM'S PRINTS.
HIS NAME'S LEONARD RAILTON,
NATIVE AMERICAN, LIVED ON
THE STORM RIVER RESERVATION.
THAT'S RIGHT NEXT
TO THE STATE FOREST.
OH, HE'S BEEN IN AND OUT
OF THE SYSTEM
SINCE HIS EARLY TEENS--
MOSTLY SMALL STUFF,
A COUPLE OF DRUG BUSTS.
NO FAMILY LISTED. HIS EMERGENCY
CONTACT IS HIS PAROLE OFFICER.
GO AND GO SHOW JANE DOE
A PICTURE OF LEONARD
AND THE LANGHAMS.
IT'S WORTH A SHOT.OKAY.
YOU GUYS CHECK OUT THE TRAIL
THAT THE LANGHAMS WERE HIKING.
IT SOUNDS LIKE
SOMETHING'S GOING ON UP THERE.
LET'S GO TALK
TO RAILTON'S P.O.[lowered voice] HEY.
THERE'S NO POINT IN HIDING
YOUR FRUSTRATION WITH HIGHTOWER.
I MEAN, SOONER OR LATER,
YOU'RE JUST GONNA EXPLODE
WITH SUPPRESSED RAGE.
WITH ANY LUCK,
YOU'LL BE NEXT TO ME.
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
I'M WORRIED ABOUT.
GRACE.
YOU OKAY?
SURE. [sighs]
NO. YOU?
THIS IS A GOOD THING, OKAY?
NO MORE SNEAKING AROUND. WE GET
TO DECIDE WHAT WE WANNA DO.DO WE KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
LET'S JUST GET THROUGH THE DAY,
AND THEN TONIGHT,
WE'LL OPEN UP A BOTTLE OF WINE
AND WE'LL TALK, OKAY?YEAH. SOUNDS GOOD.
[whispers] I LOVE YOU.[whispers] I LOVE YOU.
[woman] I THOUGHT LEONARD
HAD A CHANCE, YOU KNOW?
GOOD KID. REALLY TRYING
NOT TO REPEAT OLD MISTAKES.
HOW LONG WERE YOU LEONARD'S
PAROLE OFFICER, MS. BRINTON?
A LITTLE OVER A YEAR.
HE HAVE ANY FAMILY
WE SHOULD SPEAK TO?
NO, LEONARD DIDN'T HAVE
ANYBODY.
BUT HIS MOTHER WAS SHOSHONE,
GREW UP ON THE RESERVATION.
THAT'S WHY I GOT HIM TO MOVE
THERE AFTER HE WAS RELEASED.WHY THE RESERVATION?
LEONARD NEEDED PEOPLE
IN HIS LIFE WHO CARED ABOUT HIM.
HE COULD GET THAT THERE.
IT'S A SMALL COMMUNITY--
NOT TOO WELL-OFF, BUT TIGHT.DO YOU LIVE THERE?
MM-HMM. MY FATHER'S CLAN IS
FROM THERE. I'M SHOSHONE.
SHOSHONE, UH,
WITH A NEW YORK ITALIAN/IRISH
THING GOING ON,
IF I'M NOT MISTAKEN
BY THE ACCENT.
IS THAT
FROM YOUR MOTHER'S SIDE?
I'M NOT THE FIRST PERSON
WHO NEEDED TIME
TO FIGURE OUT WHO SHE WAS.MM.
WERE THERE ANY INDICATIONS
THAT LEONARD WAS DOING
ANYTHING ILLEGAL?
NO. HE HAD SOME PROBLEMS
WHEN HE FIRST GOT THERE,
BUT ABOUT SIX MONTHS AGO,
HE SETTLED DOWN, GOT A JOB,
HAD A GIRLFRIEND
IN THE VALLEY.WHAT WAS HER NAME?
DERRIEN HOPWOOD.
I MET HER A COUPLE OF TIMES.
NO RECORD.
GOOD INFLUENCE,
I THOUGHT.
IS THIS HER?
UH... NO,
I DON'T KNOW THIS WOMAN.
POSITIVE?I SAID NO.
I GOT IT.
DOES LEONARD HAVE ANY FRIENDS
ON THE RESERVATION
WE SHOULD TALK TO?YOU'RE GOING ON THE REZ?
YEAH.WILL THE TRIBAL POLICE BE
WITH YOU?
OH, THEY'RE AWARE
OF THE INVESTIGATION.
WE'LL KEEP THEM IN THE LOOP.I SHOULD GO WITH YOU.
OH, THAT'S NOT NECESSARY.
AS FAR AS SOME OF THEM
ARE CONCERNED,
YOU'RE FOREIGNERS--
FOREIGNERS WITH BADGES.
YOU WON'T GET ANYTHING.
I'LL GET MY COAT.
EXCELLENT. WELL,
WE GOT OURSELVES A NATIVE GUIDE.
YES.
[Rigsby]
JANINE AND MITCHELL LANGHAM.
RING ANY BELLS?[sighs] NO,
BUT I DON'T REALLY MEET PEOPLE
UNLESS THEY'RE IN TROUBLE.WELL, THESE PEOPLE GOT
INTO TROUBLE.
BEEN ANY REPORTS
OF CRIME ON THE TRAILS?
ROBBERIES, ASSAULTS?NO, JUST, YOU KNOW, RACCOONS,
BIRDS, DEER, RATTLESNAKES, BEAR.
WELL, I DON'T THINK
A BEAR SHOT FOUR PEOPLE
WITH A HIGH-POWERED RIFLE.NO, BEARS CAN'T DO THAT.
THEIR NEIGHBOR SAID
THE LANGHAMS WOULD'VE WALKED
THE MORNINGSTAR TRAIL.HUH. MORNINGSTAR IS NOT
ONE OF OUR MORE POPULAR TRAILS.
[indistinct radio chatter]EXCUSE ME. I GOT--UH...
UH, TISDALE, STAND BY ONE.
LOOK, I GOTTA GO.
I GOTTA GO UP THE HILL THERE.
WE HAVE
AN ANIMAL CONTROL ISSUE.
WELL, WE NEED TO CHECK OUT
THAT TRAIL.[sighs] OKAY, UH...
OKAY, THE TRAILHEAD
IS RIGHT OVER THERE.
YOU JUST STAY ON THE PATH.
WHEN YOU GET TO THE FORK,
YOU GO TO THE LEFT, OKAY?
JUST STAY TO THE LEFT.
YOU'LL BE FINE.
GOT IT. LEFT. THANKS.
[woman] I DON'T RECOGNIZE
ANY OF THEM.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
THINK ABOUT IT.
I HAVE. THESE PEOPLE ARE
ALL DEAD, RIGHT?
YES.
THERE'S ONE PIECE
OF GOOD NEWS.
WE RAN YOU THROUGH
THE FINGERPRINTS DATABASE.
YOU'RE NOT THERE.
HOW IS THAT GOOD NEWS?
IT MEANS
YOU'RE NOT A CRIMINAL...
ORYOU'RE
A VERY, VERY GOOD ONE.
[chuckles]
HOW'S IT GOING
WITH THE, UM...
MISSING PERSONS THING?
WELL, NO ONE'S FILED
A MISSING PERSONS REPORT
FITTING YOUR DESCRIPTION
YET,
BUT I'M SURE
IT'S JUST A MATTER OF TIME.
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
LOOK, YOU HAD A JOB TO DO,
AND YOU DID IT. THANKS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO STAY.
I'LL STICK AROUND.
[voice breaking] OKAY.
THANKS.
I'VE GOT A LOT OF TIME
INVESTED HERE,
BUT IF SHE LEAVES, WE'RE INTO
THIS WHOLE SEXISM THING
OF WHOSE JOB IS
MORE IMPORTANT.
LIKE I SAID,
IT'S COMPLICATED.NO, IT ISN'T.
WHAT?WHICH DO YOU WANT MORE--
YOUR JOB OR VAN PELT?
WHAT? IT--IT'S NOT THAT EASY.SURE IT IS.
THIS IS THE FORK, RIGHT?
NO, WE--WE TOOK THE FORK.NO, I DON'T THINK
THAT WAS THE FORK.
I THINK THIS IS THE FORK.WELL, WHATEVER. GO LEFT.
IT'S NOT THAT SIMPLE.
JOB OR VAN PELT.
ALL THERE IS TO IT.
[Brinton] THE REC CENTER'S
THE COMMUNITY GATHERING SPOT.
LEONARD USED TO COME HERE.
THIS IS JOSEPH SILVERWING.
HE HELPED
TO SETTLE LEONARD IN HERE.
HE'S ON THE TRIBAL COUNCIL.
JOSEPH, THESE ARE THE DETECTIVES
FROM CBI I CALLED YOU ABOUT.TERESA LISBON. HI.
PATRICK JANE.
WE'RE INVESTIGATING THE MURDER
OF LEONARD RAILTON.
CAN YOU TELL US ANYTHING
ABOUT HIM?
HE'S A GOOD KID. WORKED HARD.
STAYED OUT OF TROUBLE.
WE HEARD HE HAD A JOB.
DOWN AT, UH,
MARKHAM WILLIS'S PLACE.
IT'S A SOUVENIR SHOP
JUST OFF THE RESERVATION.
WAS LEONARD HAVING
ANY PROBLEMS?
NO.
DID YOU HEAR ABOUT
ANY ARGUMENTS OR FIGHTS?
NO.
MONEY PROBLEMS?
HEALTH ISSUES?
NO.
YOU'RE RIGHT. YOU REALLY ARE
OPENING THINGS UP HERE.
DO YOU KNOW ABOUT
ANY RELATIONSHIPS
HE WAS HAVING
OFF THE RESERVATION MAYBE?NO.
[indistinct conversations]
NICE SHOT.
DID YOU GUYS KNOW
LEONARD RAILTON?
[tap, balls clatter]
I'LL TAKE THAT AS A YES.
I'M TRYING TO FIND
THE PERSON WHO KILLED HIM.
DO YOU WANT TO HELP ME
WITH THAT?
DON'T ALL SPEAK AT ONCE.
WHO'S GONNA TALK FIRST?
[chuckles]
WE DON'T TALK TO PO-PO.
PO-PO?
I LIKE THAT.
BUT I'M NOT PO-PO.
I'M A PO-PO CONSULTANT.
HOW ABOUT THIS?
I BET THAT I CAN SINK A BALL
BEFORE YOUR BEST PLAYER CAN,
AND HE CAN HAVE
THREE CHANCES TO MY ONE,
AND IF I LOSE...
50 BUCKS. HUH?
BUT IF I WIN,
YOU TELL ME ABOUT LEONARD.
WE GOT A DEAL?
GREAT.
WHO'S YOUR SHARPSHOOTER?
IT'S YOU, ISN'T IT, SHORTY?
LET'S DO THIS.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
FIRST BALL IN WINS.
[balls clatter]
YOU GET THREE CHANCES.
I GET ONE.
OKAY.
AND BY THE WAY,
THAT GIRL YOU'RE CRUSHING ON,
THE ONE IN THE BLUE SWEATER--
IT'S NEVER GONNA HAPPEN.
SHE'S INTO THE TALL GUY.
GOOD LUCK.
MY MONEY'S ON THE KID.
[Patrick] ONE.
TWO.
LAST TIME. GOOD LUCK.
LUCKY LAST.
THAT'S THREE.
THERE'S A HOLE
IN THAT BALL.[ball clatters]
HERE'S THE HARD PART.
[groans]
[Patrick groans]
OOH! SCHOOLED YA.
OKAY, SO, UH,
WHAT WAS LEONARD'S STORY?
HE HAD MONEY.
A LOT OF IT.
ALWAYS HAD
THE NEWEST KICKS.
SINCE WHEN?
LIKE, SIX MONTHS AGO.
WELL, I HEARD
HE HAD A JOB.
[scoffs] OH, YEAH.
AT WILLIS'S SOUVENIR SHOP?
THAT'S PENNIES.
LEONARD HAD MONEY.
ANY IDEA WHERE THAT
MIGHT HAVE COME FROM?
HE WOULDN'T SAY.
BUT HE WAS OUT IN THE WOODS
ALL THE TIME,
SO... WE FIGURED,
YOU KNOW?
YES?
[chuckles] EVERYBODY KNOWS
WHAT GOES ON IN THE WOODS.
[chuckles] OH, SURE.
THE WOODS.
YEAH,
THIS IS NOT THE TRAIL.
IT'S OVER HERE.
ARE YOU SURE? I THOUGHT
I SAW IT OVER HERE.
WATER TANK?
[Rigsby] CHO?
YEAH?
THERE'S A POT PLANT HERE.
ACTUALLY, THERE'S A WHOLE BUNCH
OF POT PLANTS HERE.
IT LOOKS LIKE A FARM.OH, YEAH,
WHICH MEANS THERE'S PROBABLY
SOME BAD GUYS WITH GUNS.
[gunshots]
[pants]
[pants] NO BARS.
SO MUCH FOR BACKUP.
[gunshots]
[panting]THERE'S ONLY ONE SHOOTER.
YOU DRAW FIRE,
AND I'LL TAKE HIM FROM THE SIDE.
READY? ONE... TWO...ONE... TWO...
THREE!GO.
RIGSBY! CLEAR!
GOT IT!
[both panting]
IT'S THE KIND OF FARM YOU FIND
ALL OVER PUBLIC LANDS--
ABOUT AN ACRE OF PLANTS,
IRRIGATION PIPES EVERYWHERE.[Cho] MUST BE TAPPING
INTO WATER FROM UP THE VALLEY.
DID YOU HIT THE SHOOTER?
MAYBE HE'S IN A HOSPITAL.DIDN'T SEE ANY BLOOD.
I DOUBT IT.
DO YOU THINK THE RANGER
KNOWINGLY DIRECTED YOU
TOWARD THE POT FARM?
WAS THIS A SETUP?IT'S HARD TO SAY.
WE GOT PRETTY TURNED AROUND.
I'M NOT EXACTLY SURE
WE WERE ON THE TRAIL.WHERE'S THE RANGER NOW?
UP IN THE MOUNTAINS. SUPERVISOR
SAYS HE'S OUT OF CALLING RANGE.FIND OUT WHEN HE'S BACK.
SO IT LOOKS LIKE LEONARD RAILTON
WAS WORKING FOR THE POT FARMERS.
THERE'S A HUNDRED WAYS
THAT COULD TURN UGLY.MEH. IF LEONARD WAS FARMIN'
THE WEED,
HE WOULD'VE TOLD HIS FRIENDS
ABOUT IT.
WHATEVER HE WAS DOING,
HE FELT SHAME OR AMBIVALENCE.
WHICH TAKES
THE INVESTIGATION WHERE?
WELL, WE HAVEN'T SPOKEN
TO THE GIRLFRIEND YET.
SO GO DO THAT.
YOU TWO TALK TO NARCOTICS.
SEE IF THERE'S A LINE ON
MARIJUANA PLAYERS IN THAT AREA.
YOU HEARD WHAT SHE SAID.
WE WEREN'T LIVING TOGETHER
OR ANYTHING, JUST HANGING OUT.
SO LEONARD ISN'T
THE BABY'S FATHER, MS. HOPWOOD?
KAI'S FATHER?
[laughs] NO.
[Kai fusses]
OH, YEAH. I KNOW, HONEY.
BUT LEONARD LIKED
YOUR LITTLE BOY, DIDN'T HE?
SURE. [chuckles]
LEONARD BOUGHT
MOST OF THE TOYS HERE.AND THIS, UH...
ENORMOUS STACK
OF INFANT FORMULA.
YEAH, LIKE,
1,000 BUCKS WORTH.
[Kai fusses]
WHAT'S THE STORY
WITH THAT?
WELL, IT'S BECAUSE KAI GOT
THIS RASH.
IT WAS GOING AROUND, YOU KNOW?
A COUPLE OF KIDS HAD IT.
HE HAD THIS IDEA
IT WAS THE POWDERED FORMULA.
HE MADE ME THROW
ALL THE POWDERED OUT,
WHICH IS CRAZY,
'CAUSE IT'S CHEAPER,
AND IT'S REAL EASY TO USE.
ALL YOU DO IS ADD WATER.
[chuckles]
HOW'S THE RASH NOW?
[fusses]ALL GONE.
[chuckles]
I GUESS HE WAS RIGHT.
YOU WEREN'T SURPRISED TO HEAR
ABOUT LEONARD, WERE YOU?
I MEAN,
YOU--YOU CARED FOR HIM,
BUT YOU WEREN'T STARTLED
TO LEARN THAT HE WAS DEAD.
HE HAD MONEY,
AND NOT FROM
THAT LAME SOUVENIR STORE JOB.
HE WOULDN'T TELL ME
WHERE HE WAS GETTIN' IT.
MY EXPERIENCE IS,
THAT MEANS TROUBLE.
YOUR BEST GUESS?
WHATEVER ELSE
HE WAS DOING...
[Kai fussing]
HE--HE WAS ALWAYS GOOD
TO ME AND KAI.
HE WAS A GOOD MAN.
YOU FIND WHO DID THIS.
WE'LL DO EVERYTHING WE CAN.
[makes popping sound]
[gasping]
[imitates baby gurgling]
[Lisbon] MR. WILLIS, HOW LONG
WAS LEONARD WORKING HERE?[packages rustle]
UH...
I GUESS ABOUT SIX MONTHS.
I HIRED HIM ON DOLORES BRINTON'S
RECOMMENDATION.
HE WAS A GREAT KID,
GOOD WORKER.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING 'BOUT.
PRETTY GREAT, HUH?
THIS IS FANTASTIC.
D-DO YOU DELIVER?
AS A MATTER OF FACT, WE DO.ALL RIGHT.
JANE, PUT IT BACK.WHAT?
YOU HEARD ME. NOW.OKAY.
NOW!
ALL RIGHT.
WE THINK THAT, UH,
LEONARD WAS GETTING MONEY
FROM SOMEPLACE ELSE.
ANY IDEA WHAT THAT WAS ABOUT?NO. HE NEVER SAID A WORD
ABOUT IT. WHAT WAS HE DOING?
WE'RE STILL WORKING
ON THAT.
I CAN GIVE YOU A DEAL
ON THAT BONNET.
SPECIAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT DISCOUNT.
[chuckles]
YOU'RE NOT SELF-CONSCIOUS
ABOUT PEDDLING
YOUR OWN CULTURE, ARE YOU?
[chuckles]
THIS IS NOT MY CULTURE.
THIS WAR BONNET IS
FROM THE LAGUNA PEOPLE.
MM.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH US SHOSHONE.
IT'S KIND OF A PASTICHE,
REALLY.
BUT THAT'S WHAT
YOU AMERICANS WANT TO BUY,
SO THAT'S WHAT I SELL.THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME,
MR. WILLIS. JANE?
JANE!
I'LL MEET YOU OUTSIDE.
IS THERE SOME KIND OF SERVICE
FOR LEONARD?
TOMORROW AFTERNOON,
I BELIEVE.
AH.
THAT'S SUCH A SHAME.
I'M GONNA TAKE THAT.
AND I LIKE THIS ONE, TOO.
IT'S REALLY BEAUTIFUL.
SO THAT AS WELL,
AND, UM...
THIS THING. I'LL SEE
IF I CAN GET A TUNE OUT OF THAT.
JUST LOVE THOSE FEATHERS.
YEAH.MM.
[plays notes]
GRACE, HI. IT'S JANE.
HOW'S IT GOING WITH JANE DOE
THERE? SHE GET A CLUE YET?
MM, DIDN'T THINK SO.
YOU KNOW, BRING HER
DOWN TO THE OFFICE.
I THINK WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO GET
A LITTLE MORE INTERVENTIONIST.
[Patrick] OKAY.
IF YOU START TO FEEL DIZZY
OR WOOZY OR--OR ANYTHING--
GRACE, QUIT HOVERING.
ALL RIGHT? SHE'S FINE.
I TOOK HER
OUT OF THE HOSPITAL, JANE.
SHE'S MY RESPONSIBILITY.I GET THAT, BUT SHE'S FINE.
AREN'T YOU?
WHAT ARE THESE?
OH, THESE ARE PICTURES
OF WHERE YOU'RE FROM.
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE I'M FROM.
SURE YOU DO.
I'LL LAY MONEY ON THE FACT
THAT YOU'RE A LOCAL.
YOU HAVE ROOTS AROUND HERE.
YOU VISITED PLACES LIKE THIS
AS A KID.
ONE OF THESE PICTURES HERE
WILL MEAN SOMETHING TO YOU.
I GET NOTHING FROM THAT.
WHAT ABOUT THIS? HMM?
GRACE, A MINUTE?
OH, SURE.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
OKAY.
THIS?
MNH-MNH.
JUST RELAX.
DON'T WORK SO HARD.
LOOK AT THAT.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
A MORE BEAUTIFUL,
MORE PEACEFUL PLACE?
IT WOULD BE COOL
IF I COULD JUST SAY THE WORD,
AND YOU COULD BE
RIGHT THERE,
LISTENING
TO THE BIRDS SING...
[lowers voice] THE WIND RUSTLING
THROUGH THE TREES...
THE WATER LAPPING
AGAINST THE SHORE.
IF I COULD JUST SAY THE WORD.
[telephone rings]
[sighs]
WAYNE, THIS COULDN'T WAIT?
THIS IS SO SIMPLE.
I LOVE YOU...
MORE THAN--MORE THAN THIS JOB,
MORE THAN ANYTHING.
[sighs]
YOU GOT SHOT AT TODAY.
YOU'RE PUMPED FULL
OF ADRENALINE.NO, NO.
WELL, YES,
BUT THAT DOESN'T MATTER.
[gulps]
I KNOW WHAT I WANT TO DO.
[inhales deeply]
I, UH...
I TALKED TO A GUY IN
THE SAN FRANCISCO OFFICE TODAY.
THERE'S AN OPENING
IN THE MAJOR CRIMES UNIT.
IT'S ONLY
AN HOUR AND A HALF AWAY.
YOU MEAN IT?PLEASE, LET'S JUST DO THIS.
I-I DON'T CARE
WHERE I WORK.
I-I WANT YOU.
YOU REALLY MEAN IT?
[whispers] YES, YES.
REALLY? NOW?
RANGER TISDALE SHOULD BE OFF
THE MOUNTAIN IN AN HOUR, SO...
HIS BANK RECORDS SAY
HE'S DEPOSITING 2 GRAND A MONTH
OVER AND ABOVE HIS SALARY--
CASH.
LET'S GO TALK TO HIM.
TISDALE.
I WAS GONNA CALL YOU.
I JUST HEARD.
POT FARM.
DOESN'T THAT BEAT EVERYTHING?
YEAH,
RIGHT IN YOUR OWN WOODS.YEAH. I'VE BEEN HIKING
THESE TRAILS FOR EIGHT YEARS.
I HAD NO IDEA. I DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU ENDED UP,
BUT YOU MUST'VE GOTTEN
SERIOUSLY TURNED AROUND.
THAT'S HARD TO BELIEVE
WHEN THE POT FARMERS ARE
PAYING YOU $2,000 A MONTH.
2 TH--I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO COME WITH US.
[thud]OH!
[grunts][grunts]
[both grunting]
NICE WORK.
[panting] FELT GOOD.
[chuckles]
SEND YOU TO THE FARM?
I WAS TRYING LIKE HELL
TO KEEP YOU AWAY FROM IT.
ALL YOU HAD TO DO
WAS STAY ON THE TRAIL.
IS THAT REALLY SO HARD?SO YOU WERE TAKING MONEY
FROM THE POT DEALERS
TO PROTECT THEIR FARM,
RIGHT?[sighs] THEY WERE PAYING ME
TO DIRECT TOURISTS AWAY
AND LET 'EM KNOW
IF THERE WERE ANY LOCAL COPS
OR FEDS SNOOPING AROUND.
OKAY, THESE PEOPLE WHO GOT
KILLED--I NEVER EVEN SAW THEM.
I NEED THE NAMES
OF THE PEOPLE WHO PAID YOU.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
LOOK, THESE AREN'T HIPPIES
GROWING WEED IN THE FOREST,
OKAY?
THESE ARE
SERIOUS, SERIOUS MEN.
IF THEY LEARN THAT
I GAVE UP THEIR NAMES,
THEY'LL KILL ME.
LOOK, THEY KNOW
YOU'VE BEEN ARRESTED.
THEY THINK YOU'RE
GIVING THEM UP RIGHT NOW.
NOW WITH THESE MEN WALKING
AROUND, YOU'RE IN DANGER.
GIVE US THEIR NAMES,
AND WE'LL LOCK THEM UP.NO, I CAN'T.
IT'S YOUR CALL.
YOU GOT A FAMILY?UH, YEAH.
WELL, I SUGGEST
YOU SEND THEM SOMEWHERE.
NOT OUT OF TOWN--
GET 'EM OUT OF STATE.
KNOW ANYBODY ON THE EAST COAST?NO.
THAT'S TOO BAD.
HOW ABOUT OVERSEAS?
THAT'S A FIRST-RATE INTERVIEWER
YOU GOT THERE.THANK YOU.
HEY, WHAT'S UP?
SO RIGSBY AND CHO TELL ME THERE
WAS ONLY ONE DUDE WITH A GUN.
THAT DOESN'T SEEM LIKE MUCH.NO, IT'S NOT.
SO WHEN YOU SAY,
"THESE ARE NOT HIPPIES,
THESE ARE SERIOUS, SERIOUS MEN,"
THAT IMPLIES MANY SCARY MEN
WITH LARGE GUNS, RIGHT?
YES.SO WHY JUST ONE?
I DON'T KNOW.
THEY MIGHT BE LOW ON MONEY.
I MEAN,
THE--THE CROP IS DOING BADLY.PLANTS ARE DYING?
YEAH, YEAH. AND THE WORD IS
THAT IT'S BEEN GOING ON
FOR ABOUT SIX MONTHS,
AND NOBODY CAN FIGURE IT OUT,
AND THEY'RE REALLY KIND OF
FREAKING OUT ABOUT IT.I'M SURE.
JANE?YEAH?
UH, I THINK I GOTTA--
I GOTTA GO. I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
THANK YOU.
SO WHAT'D YOU GET
FROM THE GUY?
THE POT FARMERS
DIDN'T KILL LEONARD.THAT SO?
YEP.YOU CERTAIN?
WELL, CERTAINTY IS
THE MOTHER OF FOOLS.
SO ALL THIS IS JUST...
GUESSWORK WITH YOU?
PRETTY MUCH.
I MEAN, THAT'S--
THAT'S WHAT I DO, I GUESS.
FOR INSTANCE,
I GUESS THAT YOU'RE MARRIED.
I'M WEARING A RING.
WELL, I GUESS THAT YOU'RE
MARRIED, BUT NOT HAPPILY.
NOT THAT THERE'S
DIVORCE PROCEEDINGS IN PLACE,
BUT...
POSSIBLY A TRIAL SEPARATION.
GUESS I SHOULD'VE
PUT UP A PHOTO, HUH?
MM-HMM.
I KNOW YOU'RE NOT GIVING ME
RELATIONSHIP ADVICE,
SO I HAVE TO WONDER
WHY YOU WOULD GO THERE.
I GUESS IT'S YOUR WAY
OF EXPRESSING UNHAPPINESS.
MM, COULD BE.
I GUESS
IT'S YOUR WAY OF SAYING
YOU'RE UNHAPPY WITH THE WAY
I'M HANDLING LISBON.
WE SPEND
A LOT OF TIME TOGETHER.
AND WHEN SHE'S UNHAPPY,
UH, I'M LESS HAPPY.
IT'S HUMAN NATURE.
YES, IT IS.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
PATRICK.
WHY DON'T YOU LET ME
HANDLE MY BUSINESS MY WAY
AND THEN JUDGE ME
BY THE RESULTS?
AND I'LL LET YOU
HANDLE YOURS YOUR WAY...
UP TO A POINT.
THAT SOUNDS FAIR.
YEAH, VERY FAIR. WE DONE?
NO.
PLEASE DON'T INTERRUPT
INTERROGATIONS.
IT'S RUDE.THAT'S A RULE, IS IT?
GUIDELINE.
I'LL KEEP IT IN MIND.
NOW WE'RE DONE.
LOVING THOSE PUMPS.
THANK YOU.
BYE.
[blinds clatter]
[typing]
OH, WHAT'S THIS?
INTERESTING.
[lowered voice]
WE NEED TO TAKE AMNESIA GIRL
UP TO THE RESERVATION.
MEET ME IN THE PARKING LOT
IN TEN MINUTES.[lowered voice] WHY TAKE HER
TO THE RESERVATION?
THEY'RE HOLDING A MEMORIAL
FOR LEONARD RAILTON.
SHE SHOULD BE THERE.
SHE MIGHT REMEMBER SOMETHING.WORTH A TRY, I GUESS.
OH, DO ME A FAVOR.HMM?
DON'T MENTION THIS
TO LISBON OR HIGHTOWER.AND WHY NOT?
WELL, WHY COMPLICATE THINGS?COMPLICATE HOW?
HELL, VAN PELT,
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE TAKEN HER
OUT OF THE HOSPITAL
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
YOUR CAR,
PARKING LOT, TEN MINUTES.
[man chanting in
Native American language]
MR. JANE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WELL, WE'RE HERE
TO PAY OUR RESPECTS.
IT'S OKAY.
WE WON'T EAT MUCH.
LEONARD HAD ONLY BEEN WITH US
A SHORT WHILE,
BUT IF YOU SAW HIM
WALKING A TRAIL UP AT THE LAKES
OR RIDING A HORSE,
YOU COULD SEE
THAT HE WAS HOME.
SO REMEMBER THE OLD WORDS.
WHEN A FRIEND DIES,
WE SHOULD NOT CRY.
WE SHOULD NOT HATE SOMEONE
OR FIGHT.
WE SHOULD DO RIGHT ALWAYS.
AND WE SHOULD LISTEN
TO THE OLD WORDS
AND REMEMBER LEONARD.
IF ANYONE ELSE
HAS SOMETHING TO SAY...
OH, I WOULD.
THIS WOMAN WAS WITH LEONARD
WHEN HE WAS SHOT.
SHE HAS LOST HER MEMORY.
SO WE BROUGHT HER HERE TODAY
TO SEE IF A FACE
OR A PLACE OR ANYTHING
COULD HELP HER REMEMBER
WHO SHE IS.
THIS IS KIND OF A SACRED MOMENT.
IS THIS REALLY THE TIME?
IT'LL TAKE BUT A SECOND.
[Patrick] ANYTHING?
NO.
NEVER MIND. THE TRIP
WAS NOT ENTIRELY WASTED.
I WAS ALSO LOOKING AT ALL OF YOU
TO SEE IF ANYONE RECOGNIZED HER.
AND IT SEEMS TO ME THAT SOMEBODY
HERE DOESKNOW THIS WOMAN.
AND THAT SOMEBODY
IS YOU, SIR.
ME?
I THINK YOU'RE MISTAKEN.
PROVE IT.
[grunts] HOW?
LOOK INTO MY EYES
AND HOLD THIS.
NOW TELL ME
YOU DON'T KNOW HER.
I DO NOT KNOW THIS WOMAN.
OKAY.
UM, UM, OKAY.
IT APPEARS
THAT I'M MISTAKEN,
WHICH IS VERY GOOD FOR YOU.
THAT ELIMINATES YOU
FROM OUR INQUIRY.
MY APOLOGIES. CARRY ON. WE'LL
JUST TAKE OUR SEATS IN THE BACK.
THANK YOU.
AND, LISTEN, IF YOU--
IF YOU DON'T WANT US HERE,
THEN JUST SAY THE WORD
AND WE'LL GO. JUST SAY THE WORD.
[Joseph] I THINK
IT WOULD BE BETTER--I SEE IT.
I SEE IT! I SEE IT! I SEE IT!
I SEE IT.
[laughing]
NOW JUST RELAX, BREATHE
AND TELL US WHAT YOU SEE.
THERE'S A BLUE LAKE...
PINE TREES...
A MOUNTAIN...
THERE'S A BIRD SINGING.
TELL US WHAT'S HAPPENING
AT THIS LAKE.
IT'S WHERE
THE BAD THING HAPPENED.
WHAT BAD THING?
GO LOOK. THEY...
THEY LEFT SOMETHING
ON THE SHORE.
WHO DID?GO LOOK.
THEY LEFT SOMETHING.
[whispers]
I'M SORRY.
OKAY, SHOW'S OVER. COME ON.
WATCH YOUR HEAD.
SO MR. SILVERWING IS
GONNA COMPLAIN TO OUR SUPERIORS
IN THE STRONGEST TERMS.
NICE WORK.
SEE, THAT'S WHY I DIDN'T BRING
YOU ALONG--DENIABILITY.
HOW DID YOU KNOW WE WERE HERE?I HAD LITTLE, TINY
G.P.S. TRACKERS
SEWN INTO ALL YOUR SUITS.
FOR A SECOND THERE, I ALMOST
BELIEVED YOU. GRACE?
SORRY, JANE.
I HAD TO TELL HER. IT'S MY JOB.EH, THAT'S NOT IT.
GET HER BACK TO THE HOSPITAL.YES, BOSS.
SHE DIDREMEMBER SOMETHING.
WE HAVE A CLUE.
A LAKE IN THE MOUNTAIN,
SOMETHING ON THE SHORE?
COULD BE WHERE
THE MURDERS HAPPENED.THERE'S OVER 50 LAKES
IN THOSE MOUNTAINS!
I'LL TAKE HER BACK
TO THE HOSPITAL.LISTEN, I'M SORRY I DIDN'T
TELL YOU WHERE I WAS GOING.
I WASTRYING
TO PROTECT YOU.
I KNEW I WAS
GONNA STIR THINGS UP,
AND, WHAT, WITH HIGHTOWER ALL-- DON'T.DON'T EVER TRY
TO PROTECT ME.
I CAN PROTECT MYSELF
FROM HIGHTOWER OR ANYBODY ELSE.OKAY.
LET'S GO BACK
TO THE OFFICE.WE COULD.
OR WE COULD STAY HERE
AND CATCH
LEONARD RAILTON'S KILLER.HOW ARE WE GONNA DO THAT?
I NEED A CUP.
PAPER OR PLASTIC--
I'D PREFER PAPER.[car door opens]
[car door slams]SO JANE DOE
DIDN'T REMEMBER THE LAKE?
POSTHYPNOTIC SUGGESTION.
I SHOWED HER A BEAUTIFUL PICTURE
OF A LAKE AND TOLD HER
THAT SHE WOULD REMEMBER IT WHEN
SHE HEARD THE TRIGGER PHRASE--
"SAY THE WORD." SHE REMEMBERED
THE PICTURE, ASSOCIATED IT
WITH THE CRIME AND FELT THAT
SOMETHING WAS LEFT BEHIND THERE.WHAT SOMETHING?
WELL, IT--IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THE KILLER'S FEELING
PARANOID NOW, SO HE OR SHE
WILL BE COMPELLED TO GO BACK
TO THE SCENE OF THE CRIME
AND MAKE SURE THAT
NOTHING WAS LEFT BEHIND.THAT'S ASSUMING THE MURDER
OCCURRED AT THE LAKE.
WELL, IT DID.BECAUSE?
BECAUSETHE POT CROP DIED,
AND LEONARD RAILTON WAS WORRIED
ABOUT THE WATER HIS
GIRLFRIEND'S BABY WAS GETTING.
HEY, IT'S OVER HERE.AND THE WATER SUPPLY
FOR AROUND HERE
COMES FROM THE MOUNTAIN LAKES.
CHO FOLLOWED THE KILLER
AFTER THE MEMORIAL.
AND? WHO IS IT?WE'LL SEE.
WHERE IS HE?
[Cho]
STRAIGHT THROUGH THE TREES.
[tapping][Cho] HANDS UP.
WHAT'S GOING ON?GET YOUR HANDS UP.
NO, I-I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
RIFLE SHELL.
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT,
MR. WILLIS?
I JUST FOUND IT.
I WAS GONNA GIVE IT TO YOU.
DO YOU THINK
IT'S CONNECTED TO THOSE MURDERS?[laughing]
THAT'S THE BEST YOU GOT?WHY'D YOU SHOOT
THOSE FOUR PEOPLE, MR. WILLIS?
I DIDN'T.WELL, KEEP IN MIND
THAT TWO OF THEM--
THE LANGHAMS--THEY WERE,
UH, BY-PRODUCTS, LATECOMERS.
BUT LEONARD...
LEONARD YOU KILLED BECAUSE OF
WHAT'S IN THE LAKE, DIDN'T YOU?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
TOXIC WASTE.
GREAT, BIG BARRELS OF IT,
I EXPECT.
DUMPED BY YOU.
THAT'S WHY THE POT PLANTS
IN THE VALLEY WERE DYING.
THAT'S WHY DERRIEN HOPWOOD'S
CHILD GOT A RASH.
LEONARD WAS GONNA TELL,
SO YOU HAD TO SHOOT HIM.
AND ANYONE ELSE THAT JUST...
HAPPENED TO COME ALONG THAT DAY.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
THAT IS NOTTRUE.
WELL, THIS IS GROUND ZERO
FOR THE DUMPING,
SO THE WATER HERE MUST BE
MUCH MORE TOXIC
THAN IT IS DOWN IN THE VALLEY.THAT IS NONSENSE!
[Patrick] REALLY?
FEELING A LITTLE PARCHED?
HAVE A DRINK.
NO.
NO.WHY NOT?
OH, COME ON.
CHEERS. HAVE A DRINK.NO.
LITTLE SIP.NO. NO, PLEASE, STOP.
NO!
[grunts] ALL RIGHT!
I TRIED TO GET SO MANY IDEAS
ACROSS THE TRIBAL COUNCIL.
[sighs]
BUT SOMEBODY DIDN'T LIKE IT,
OR IT WASN'T
CULTURALLY APPROPRIATE,
OR BLAH, DE, BLAH, DE, BLAH.
SO THIS GUY SAID
HE NEEDED TO DUMP
SOME STUFF,
AND DID I KNOW ANY PLACE
ON THE REZ THAT HE COULD DO IT?
SO I HAD LEONARD TAKE THEM
UP TO THE LAKE.
WELL, I FIGURED WITH HIS RECORD,
HE'D TAKE THE MONEY
AND KEEP HIS MOUTH SHUT.
WELL, WE WENT WELL.
[thud] GOT MORE TRUCKS UP THERE.
I MEAN, SOMETHING WAS
FINALLY WORKING FOR ME.
AND THEN THAT KID IN THE VALLEY
GOT A RASH.
AND LEONARD WAS WORRIED.
SAID WEWERE
POISONING THE VALLEY,
AND IF WE DIDN'T STOP, THAT
HE WAS GONNA BLOW THE WHISTLE.
THEN I OVERHEARD HIM
ON THE PHONE,
ARRANGING TO MEET SOMEBODY
UP AT THE LAKE.
SO I WENT, TOO.
[gunshot]
WHEN DID THE LANGHAMS
GET THERE?
I WAS CLEANING UP.
YOU KNOW,
WHAT THEY DOING THERE, ANYWAY?
[gunshot]
UM,
THEY WERE TAKING A HIKE?
[sighs]
[voice breaking] I'M SORRY.
I AM.
[whispers] I'M SORRY.
WELL, THAT'S OKAY, THEN.
AS LONG AS YOU'RE SORRY.
MAYBE WE'LL JUST LET YOU GO.
I'M KIDDING.
[knock on window]
HEY.
GOT SOMETHING FOR YOU.
YOUR DRIVER'S LICENSE.
WE GOT IT
FROM MARKHAM WILLIS.
YOUR NAME IS CAMILLE DILLON.
YOU LIVE IN OAKLAND.
YOU'RE AN INTERNET JOURNALIST
AND WRITER.
WE CONTACTED YOUR FAMILY.
YOUR MOM IS ON HER WAY
FROM DES MOINES.
MY NAME IS CAMILLE?
APPARENTLY,
YOU TAUGHT LEONARD RAILTON
WHILE HE WAS
IN THE JUVENILE SYSTEM.
A LITTLE WHILE AGO,
HE GOT IN TOUCH WITH YOU ABOUT--
WAIT.
SOMETHING...
SOMETHING WAS WRONG.
THEY WERE...
SOMEONE WAS, UH, DUMPING...
TOXINS.Y-YES.
AND HE--
HE WANTED PEOPLE TO KNOW. HE...
HE CALLED...
AND HE--HE ASKED
FOR MY HELP.
I REM--
I REMEMBER HIM.
I REMEMBER HIM
ASKING FOR MY HELP.
[sniffles and whispers]
I REMEMBER.
I REMEMBER ME.
[voice breaking]
I KNOW WHO I AM.
HEY. JUST LET ME
FINISH THIS UP,
AND WE'LL GO
TALK TO HIGHTOWER.
WAYNE...
WHAT'S UP?
I LOVE YOU. I DO.
BUT I THINK
I LOVE THE JOB MORE.
WELL, JOB'S NOT A PROBLEM.
I'M GONNA GO.
YOU'D BE LEAVING THE UNIT...
FOR US.
SO?
I DON'T WANT
THAT RESPONSIBILITY.
YOU'LL HATE ME FOR IT.
[voice breaking] MAYBE NOT
TODAY, BUT SOMEDAY YOU WILL.NO, GRACE, WE--WE--
[whispers] I'M SORRY.
YOU'RE, UH...
CERTAIN ABOUT THIS?
I KNOW WHO I AM.
[chair rolls]
NARCOTICS PICKED UP
THE POT FARMERS
OFF THE RANGER'S CONFESSION.
I ALSO GOT A CALL
FROM A GUY NAMED SILVERWING
ABOUT A STUNT YOU PULLED UP ON
THE STORM RIVER RESERVATION.WELL, I WOULDN'T CALL THAT
A STUNT SO M--
WHATEVER. HE WAS DISPLEASED.YES, MA'AM.
I FILLED OUT A P-90--
YOU SOLVED THE TRIPLE,
RIGHT?YEAH.
NOBODY GOT HURT?[Patrick] NO.
THEN THE HELL WITH HIM.
YOU GOT JUSTICE DONE.
KEEP UP THE GOOD WORK.
THAT WAS UNEXPECTED.
I'LL SAY.
HEY, GRACE.
HI. [sniffles][elevator bell dings]
YOU ALL RIGHT?[crying] I'M FINE.
OKAY, BUT...[sobbing]
YEAH, I-I JUST...
I JUST, UH, FORGOT MY... STUFF.
[continues sobbing]
STAY TUNED FOR SCENES
FROM OUR NEXT EPISODE.